<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-21T08:11:54+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/2025-03-22-Chronicles-I-All-Circles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-07-21T08:11:54+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T08:11:54+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/2025-03-22-Chronicles-I-All-Circles</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/2025-03-22-Chronicles-I-All-Circles/"><![CDATA[<p>I woke late at the Excalibur in room 270, floor 9. It was the first morning of my holiday. Thousands of duplicate rooms surrounded 270, all of them dingy, all of them starved of clues of the resort’s medieval theme. There were no suits of plate armour standing along the hallway, my bed was not framed with velvet drapes, and, to my disappointment, the staff at the front desk did not refer to my room as ‘your bedchamber’.</p> <p>The Excalibur was medieval-themed in the same way that a pervert’s doglike if you put a lead on them: they’re more of a dog, but rescue shelters won’t take them and they’ll continue to get digestive issues if they eat kibble. Its unrendered bulk was two imposing two-thousand room blocs adorned with a few small turrets, with a cluster of cartoonish, colourful, and strictly noninteractive towers concentrated above its main entrance.</p> <p>With the blind shut - hell, even with it open - you’d mistake the Excalibur for any other aging budget resort in Las Vegas, even if you’ve never been to Las Vegas. You wouldn’t think it’s a new one, since you’d see the surfaces in the bathroom are yellowing, there’s too much brown for anyone to have said yes, and there’s still the stale stink of cigarette smoke, despite the fact you’ll get ejected if you smoke in your room.</p> <p>The Excalibur seemed like a hotel that would be blown up soon. I don’t mean this in a sinister way. That’s what they do to old hotels in Vegas – blow them up. They replace them with a pile of rubble, which gets cleared away to make an empty lot. Then a construction site grows up out of the lot to crystallize into another hotel. After a few years of that hotel standing around aging, it too gets blown up, and the cycle starts again. I hoped I’d check out before they next blew this one up.</p> <p>So, my room wasn’t a pocket of a medieval castle, nor of a castle-themed hotel, but of a stagnating hotel wearing a cheap castle costume, which had flourished on the grave of some other hotel, and would one day get popped and mopped up to make way for something else.</p> <p> </p> <hr/> <p> </p> <p>From the snug motte of my duvet I ordered an Uber for a diner across town named Winnie &amp; Ethel’s. I dressed, left my room, and scanned along the silly long hallway to the elevators. The resort didn’t have roundtower staircases, presumably because these would be impractical for visitors with luggage, particularly those on double-digit floors, so I took an elevator down to the lobby.</p> <p>To get to the Uber pick-up spot I needed to walk through the Excalibur’s casino. I don’t know what games of chance they played in renaissance Europe, but let me tell you I’m pretty sure the Excalibur doesn’t have them, since almost all of the casino’s floorspace was reserved for either slot machines to stand in, or for seats that allowed slot machines to be sat at.</p> <p>There were two reasons I was going to a diner outside of the resort for breakfast. The first was that I was worried I might not be able to digest the food served by the resort’s fast food restaurants. I didn’t object to the food being served quickly, but they were asking people to eat the craziest things, flown or trucked into this patch of the desert specifically for dispensation to the good patrons of the Excalibur and its peer resorts. The second reason was that I was developing an insurgent mentality against the resort. I knew ahead of visiting Vegas that the hotel gambit was to offer cheap room rates in exchange for owning the slot machine closest to where you slept. But I didn’t appreciate that they applied the same logic to the closest calorie to where you slept, or the closest seat not in your room, too, and I was gradually absorbing the distressing lesson that - apart from the floor - there wasn’t a place to sit within a kilometre’s walk of my bed that would cost me less than $10.</p> <p>I cast a dirty and hungry look at the Essentials kiosk on my way out of the lobby. The kiosk and I diverged in our assessment of whether Cheetos Flamin’ Hot Puffs were essential. There were no price tags. No-one was browsing or buying. The only cue the drinks and snacks cost anything, besides the fact that they hadn’t already been taken, was the cash register and its attendant.</p> <p>I passed through a double set of double doors that led outside to the Excalibur pick-up spot. The Excalibur’s pick-up spot and drop-off spot weren’t the same place. While stood in the sun waiting for the Uber, I reflected that the drop-off spot, which was at the entrance to the resort, was sheltered and shaded and featured misters, while the pick-up spot, where I was stood, was a broad hot slate of exposed concrete looking out onto a more slabs of exposed concrete, namely a highway and a carpark. Huh.</p> <p>My Uber arrived. I got in and said hello to the driver. He looked at me warmly through the rearview mirror.</p> <p> </p> <hr/> <p> </p> <p>   “Good morning sir! Do you live in Vegas, or are you visiting?” “I’m visiting. Last night was the first night of my holiday. Does anybody that lives in Vegas stay in the Excalibur?”</p> <p>I accidentally sounded sarcastic.</p> <p>   “Well sir, you would be surprised. A lot of people still live in Vegas hotels. Lots of well-known people. There are shows every night of the year. The biggest names have shows here and they need somewhere to stay. And we’ve had the biggest of them all here. You know who I mean?”</p> <p>His lips cracked open to reveal a big smile. His reflection peered over its sunglasses at me.</p> <p>   “Elvis?” “Correct. Elvis Presley. He lived in the Westgate hotel. The biggest of them all. Elvis, I mean. He found his way here from Memphis, Tennessee. Like I always say, the circles are there if you care to look. Here, let me trace one for you.”</p> <p>He drew small rings in the air with his forefinger.</p> <p>   “I myself moved around a lot as a child, being a military dependent. My father moved for work, and so my mother and I moved too. And you know where the Navy moved him? NSA Mid-south, Millington, Tennessee, which is right outside of Memphis, Tennessee. “As a boy I visited a home in Memphis a few times. My mother and father volunteered, helped servicemen settle in. They ran bus tours of the city on weekends. My father would drive, with my mother talking and telling sailors about the city over the PA. And I would go with them. Do you know what one of the stops was on the route we took?” “Elvis’s house?” “Correct. Elvis’s house. You know what he called it? Graceland. And it was beautiful. I knew then that it was something special to me. Elvis came to Las Vegas, and so did I. My wife, she was like a wet cat, had to drag her hissin’ and scratchin’, but I kept telling her it was our path.”</p> <p>His phone, which was cradled between the driver and passenger seats, flashed with a figure of $4.44.</p> <p>   “Look! Did you see that?! Tell me you saw that! Four four four. Four dollars and forty-four cents.”</p> <p>I was unsure of the significance of the number to him and concerned what it might mean for his already erratic lane discipline.</p> <p>   “Hey Siri!” he said to the dashboard, “What is the meaning of the angel number 444?”</p> <p>Siri paused to think about it for a moment, then replied.</p> <p>   “The angel number 444 is commonly interpreted as a sign from the divine that you’re on the right track. It’s a cosmic nudge affirming that whatever is occurring in your life is meant to be and that you’re close to a new beginning.” “See! I know I am on the right track. And the universe is telling me so. I know that good things are coming. You know, I’ve set up in Elvis’s room at the Westgate. And the energy when I did so–”</p> <p>He mouthed an explosion and the eyes beneath his sunglasses blinked in soft shock.</p> <p>   “There was something in that room on that day, I tell you. So many connections! Here, let me show you another.”</p> <p>He fished around in the drivers-side sunvisor for something, then presented it to me.</p> <p>   “Take a look at my license. My name, read my name out loud.”</p> <p>A few days previous I had expressed my amazement to a cab driver that his name was Mr Desert, only to learn that I had confused his name with that of the company he drove for, Desert Cabs. I was apprehensive about making a similar mistake here, which I knew would kill the blossoming significance of the moment. I read cautiously.</p> <p>   “Eric Paul the second?” “And the surname.” “… Roulette?” “Roulette! Eric Roulette! In this city! What a way to tell me that I am on the right track and that I am meant to be here. And boy is it the right name for me. My life’s like playing roulette. I’ve had it all and lost it, then had it all again and lost it once more. “And it’s about time I had it again. I signed two en-dee-ays just last week with Universal Music. You know what Universal Music have? Universal Music have a funk label that they don’t use anymore, Roulette Records. No-one’s on it any more, they haven’t used it in years. But I’m going to ask them to give it to me. I’m going to revive it. I’m going to bring all my artists under it and you know what? There’s going to be me, at the top.”</p> <p>Eric formed his fingers into a crane and mimed planting himself on top.</p> <p> </p> <hr/> <p> </p> <p>We pulled off East Flamingo Road, one of the gigantic boulevards that transects the Las Vegas Strip, into what looked like the entrance to a multi-storey carpark. I couldn’t see Winnie &amp; Ethel’s diner.    “I would say it looks like we’re here, except it doesn’t. This is no good, let me drop you further around.”</p> <p>Eric drove on but the road looped back onto East Flamingo.</p> <p>   “Hm, looks like that was it after all. Guess I’ll just have to drop you where we were.” “Remember – it’s DJ Roulette. It was very nice meeting you, have a nice day, and be sure to look me up on YouTube. Remember to like, comment, and subscribe!”</p> <p>I thanked Eric, said I would, stepped out of the car, and waved as he pulled away. I looked around. No Winnie &amp; Ethel’s diner.</p> <p>Five years before meeting Eric, I had developed a superstition about flamingos. I hadn’t been to see a doctor about it, since I thought it was nothing. But now, in Las Vegas, after being dropped off by Eric, I was in the wrong place, and what should there be but a flamingo. Opposite me, across the boulevard, was a flamingo, the Flamingo, a historic casino slap-bang in the middle of the Strip and namesake of Flamingo Road, the first honeytrap of Vegas, a gift from gangster Bugsy Siegel.</p> <p>I checked the map, then I checked Uber. It turned out there was a dud Winnie &amp; Ethel’s marker a kilometre south of the diner’s actual location.</p> <p>Although Eric Paul Roulette II was right where he was meant to be, I, unfortunately, was not.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">twig-ii.js</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/twig-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="twig-ii.js"/><published>2025-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/twig-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/twig-2/"><![CDATA[<link href="/assets/css/sketch.css" rel="stylesheet"/> <div id="sketch"> <script src="/assets/js/twig-2.js"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="p5js"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">twig.js</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/twig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="twig.js"/><published>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/twig</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/twig/"><![CDATA[<link href="/assets/css/sketch.css" rel="stylesheet"/> <div id="sketch"> <script src="/assets/js/twig.js"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="p5js"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">jelly-wriggler.js</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/jelly-wriggler/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="jelly-wriggler.js"/><published>2025-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/jelly-wriggler</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/jelly-wriggler/"><![CDATA[<link href="/assets/css/sketch.css" rel="stylesheet"/> <div id="sketch"> <script src="/assets/js/jelly-wriggler.js"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="p5js"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">wriggler.js</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/wriggler/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="wriggler.js"/><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/wriggler</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/wriggler/"><![CDATA[<link href="/assets/css/sketch.css" rel="stylesheet"/> <div id="sketch"> <script src="/assets/js/wriggler.js"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="p5js"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">dvd.js</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/dvd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="dvd.js"/><published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/dvd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/dvd/"><![CDATA[<link href="/assets/css/sketch.css" rel="stylesheet"/> <div id="sketch"> <script src="/assets/js/dvd.js"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="p5js"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">⧉.js</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="⧉.js"/><published>2025-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/%E2%A7%89</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2025/"><![CDATA[<link href="/assets/css/sketch.css" rel="stylesheet"/> <div id="sketch"> <script src="/assets/js/⧉.js"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="p5js"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wake</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Wake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wake"/><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Wake</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Wake/"><![CDATA[<p>Sleep receives attention from the popular consciousness in spades. People would like to know how much of it to get, how to pattern it, and what sort or sorts it should be. They would like to know, for example, how to arrange their day’s last moments of wakefulness so they can visit Nod with a minimum of fuss, have a nice stay, and return home on time and without too much discomfort. Do I need a white noise machine? What about the humidifier? The autotuck-and-lullaby mattress? This ring that chants actigraphic riddles? Being harangued by bus air-brakes and bin lorries at 5am is probably a bad thing, right?</p> <p>In waltz with this popular enthusiasm for improving sleep is a surge in sleep analysis. Sleep’s been decomposed into cycles and phases to demarc repetition, sameness, variation, and innovation in the state of the sleeper, and measures of sleep quality have been crafted and correlated with various life factors such as mood, alertness, physical might, and performance on problem-solving tasks. Sleep’s been sawed up into pieces, the pieces have been labeled, and people are sifting through them trying to figure out which bits are, in fact, critical components of waking activities.</p> <p>My impression is that most of the enthusiasm about sleep is really enthusiasm about wakefulness. Make no mistake: people like sleeping, but they don’t engineer their sleep simply to improve their sleep. They do it to improve their wakefulness. You, dear reader, may even feel a tickle of curiosity about how you could make your own sleep more pleasurable for its own sake. I certainly do. But I suspect that when a person’s buying overpriced magnesium or a dehumidifier and they’re telling the cashier it’s ‘for their sleep’, the quest they’re on is likely <em>better wakefulness</em> rather than <em>better sleep</em>.</p> <p>A villain in this mix-up is the English language. English - at least, standard English - seems to conspire against speakers that try to talk about sleep and wakefulness. ‘sleep’ has a single syllable, whereas ‘wakefulness’ has three of them. Who has time to talk about wakefulness? For whatever reason, the contraction to ‘wake’ (‘asleep’ / ‘awake’, if you’re a linguist who has a better idea then write to me) hasn’t happened yet, at least not among the people I speak to and read. I have yet to be prematurely fobbed off by anyone telling me ‘I’m getting out of bed early to get a good day’s wake.’.</p> <p>Mercifully, this villain is easily defeated. We can untangle sleep discourse by removing the circumlocutory step: when interested in wakefulness, we can talk directly about wakefulness - about wake (yes, we’re going to do it).</p> <p>A rich seam for research, to my greenhorn eye, at least, is to ask analogous questions about wake that we’ve been asking about sleep. How can we split it up into phases? What is wake’s structure? How predictive are its duration and active phases of the things people care about, such as mood, physical performance, and attentional control? Occupationally, I could imagine people clamoring to see a wake specialist.</p> <p><em>So you’re interested in improving your wake, hm? And this is to improve your wake, or your sleep? Your sleep is important, you know, it depends in all sorts of ways on your wake. If you take care to wake well, your sleep will be superb. Interested in improving your wake, right… Well, perhaps a good place to start is to tell me what happens while you wake, what activities and places you find yourself in, and as you’re doing that I’ll get out my slides showing you the phases of wake…</em></p> <p>Hear the agitated honking of the two alarm clocks.</p> <p>One’s letting us know that we could be sleeping for the sake of sleeping. What makes a night’s sleep enjoyable? How can I get some of that? There are at least two subcultures dedicated specifically to an aspect of sleeping, namely lucid dreamers and polyphasic sleepers. There could be more. I can imagine the cosycore acolytes going buck wild for cosymaxed sleep. <em>Sleep for sleep’s sake</em>, their tattoos could read.</p> <p>The other alarm honks to remind us that a better day’s wake and night’s sleep are both borne from punctilious analysis and cultivation of wake, as well as sleep. The body’s passing through phases while it’s awake just like when it’s asleep. These phases interact with where you are and what you’re doing, and are linked to all sorts of things you’re interested in. And yet, I could tell you more about what happens during an R.E.M. phase of sleep than I could about any of the phases of wake.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="nonsense"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sleep receives attention from the popular consciousness in spades. People would like to know how much of it to get, how to pattern it, and what sort or sorts it should be. They would like to know, for example, how to arrange their day’s last moments of wakefulness so they can visit Nod with a minimum of fuss, have a nice stay, and return home on time and without too much discomfort. Do I need a white noise machine? What about the humidifier? The autotuck-and-lullaby mattress? This ring that chants actigraphic riddles? Being harangued by bus air-brakes and bin lorries at 5am is probably a bad thing, right?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why did Ahab want to kill Moby Dick?</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Why-Did-Ahab-Want-To-Kill-Moby-Dick/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why did Ahab want to kill Moby Dick?"/><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Why-Did-Ahab-Want-To-Kill-Moby-Dick</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Why-Did-Ahab-Want-To-Kill-Moby-Dick/"><![CDATA[<p>Why did Ahab want to kill Moby Dick? Because Moby Dick took his leg, because the ivory replacement clattered on the foredeck of the Pequod at night and prompted second mate Stubb to whinge, and because the foul mood that clings to chronic amputative pain causes a sea-captain to fester to a murderous boil. Were the truth of any of these facts different, Ahab might not have wanted to kill Moby Dick. But being true as they were and are, Ahab did want to kill Moby Dick.</p> <p>Ahab’s intention was singular. He made no attempt to conceal it. Early in the assassinative voyage he assembled the entire crew of the Pequod, whom all thought they had contracted with a commercially-motivated captain, to explain that (1) he wanted to kill Moby Dick, (2) that’s all he wanted, and (3) he wanted to kill Moby Dick for no reason other than to have killed Moby Dick. Ahab shrouded his aim in no skimask of instrumental reasons - the permacetti, the money, the legend, the reputation, the pride, the safety of other whalers, the extinguished threat of the white whale hunting him down to finish off the job. No, instead he unabashedly marked his aim out as terminal, nakedly presenting that its meaning rested on nothing but itself.</p> <p>Ahab knew the crew would only care about Moby Dick because it (he? Feels inappropriate) was another whale to include in the voyage’s catch. To spur particular interest in this one whale he offered the bounty of a gold doubloon to the harponeer that initiated its induction to the haul. But Ahab made no real attempt to bind anyone else with the same mysterious autonomic spell that transmuted him into an instrument for killing the whale, a device enraged and staminal enough to spend three treacherous years groping through all of the earth’s oceans in search of the submerged thimble of the snow hill. And, although Ahab and the crew of the Pequod knew Ahab’s intention seemed errant, and that he was executing strange commands on the bare metal of purpose, there was no dissuading him of it.</p> <p>The crew considered Ahab mad, and Ahab knew the world thought him mad. And yes, if Ahab had not wanted to kill Moby Dick, the Pequod would have likely returned safely to a New Bedford harbour. But, if Ahab had not wanted to kill Moby Dick, well, then there would be no <em>Moby Dick</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literary-criticism"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why did Ahab want to kill Moby Dick? Because Moby Dick took his leg, because the ivory replacement clattered on the foredeck of the Pequod at night and prompted second mate Stubb to whinge, and because the foul mood that clings to chronic amputative pain causes a sea-captain to fester to a murderous boil. Were the truth of any of these facts different, Ahab might not have wanted to kill Moby Dick. But being true as they were and are, Ahab did want to kill Moby Dick.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The teapot</title><link href="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Teapot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The teapot"/><published>2024-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Teapot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stochastictalk.github.io/blog/2024/Teapot/"><![CDATA[<p>The phone is cheap and small. Its screen is greasy. But let me instead tell you about the teapot, which I much prefer.</p> <p>When you look at the teapot, you think it might be a toy from a play tea set. It has bright bits. Its lid’s like an electroplated areola, ceramicised to the same shade of lime-green that gets injected into Twisters. The handle too looks tasty and inedible, a porcelain rib lovingly brushed with a single rich stroke of burgundy glaze.</p> <p>But you know the teapot is not a toy. Its handle is too big and its body too heavy to be comfortably handled by small hands. The specks of glare you see on its surfaces are hard, not soft, and so tell you that the teapot is ceramic, not plastic. Ceramic materials are no good for children’s toys. If small hands handled and dropped this teapot then it would smash. Tea and fragments of ceramic would explode and then get trodden across the floor. Disaster.</p> <p>The teapot sits quietly on the table. But, in spite of its wordlessness, you still hear almost all of its sounds. Relaxed private chatter from other tables, the groan and hiss of the coffee machine as it relieves itself, the squealing of chair legs as their chairs get tucked or untucked, and the intermittent tinkle of windchimes broadcasting another swing of the cafe’s door.</p> <p>You think to yourself that the teapot looks cosy. There are five-leaf clovers stamped in festive hues all over its enamel paunch. This and its lime green lid say that it is a character that is dressed for winter. It has its knitted sweater and bobble hat and they are exactly what it needs to keep itself and its tea warm.</p> <p>Someone clearly takes care of the teapot. It’s unchipped and is clean. At least, it’s clean unless you study where the light hits it just so, where water marks are revealed. The nipple of the lid has not yet been gripped enough for the green to have been selectively worn away to the raw enamel beneath. Peaking out of the teapot’s spout you see tea stains, but you find these charming. They just let you know that although someone finds this teapot difficult to wash, they still love it enough to keep it around.</p> <p>Glancing off of the teapot are two kinds of glare. One, scattered like fairy lights along the tops of the lid and handle, is a warm kind. The other, glued like a melted postage stamp to the teapot’s side, is cool. Together they tell you which way is inside, which way is outside, what time of day it is, and which way is up. They make you feel glad to be where you are.</p> <p>If you pick up the teapot and raise it over your head, a risky maneuver, you can see its base. It is stained with a blue seal. When first stamped, the letters of this seal seeped a little, but they froze into type that’s clear enough to read now. It says ‘Whittard’. The teapot’s name? It’s progenitor? This is a teapot that is proud of itself. You suspect this is an important teapot, one that was carefully chosen.</p> <p>A teacup accompanies the teapot on the table. Like the teapot, it too is wearing a porcelain jumper adorned with festive clovers, and it too has a burgundy ribbon, this one finely wrapped around its lip. But the teacup has no lime-green lid. Since it has no lid, its inside is exposed to the elements. Thankfully, possibly because of the good fortune brought by the clovers, it does not need to worry, since it has the teapot nearby for warmth.</p> <p>At just this moment, however, the teacup must be getting cold, since the tea has nearly been completely drained from it. It is not being refilled. What tea is left is lurking evasively at the bottom of the cup’s basin. The teacup will soon be cleared away and the teapot will be cleared away with it. And then? You will no longer be able to look at the teapot.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="short-story"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The phone is cheap and small. Its screen is greasy. But let me instead tell you about the teapot, which I much prefer.]]></summary></entry></feed>